<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on Kyle Mapue</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on Kyle Mapue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Journey: From kubectl to GitOps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-kubernetes-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-kubernetes-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone diving into DevOps, there&amp;rsquo;s a moment when the theory of Kubernetes—all the talk of Pods, Services, and Deployments—needs to meet the messy reality of practice. My journey with the &amp;ldquo;Log-Pong&amp;rdquo; application was exactly that: a hands-on, often challenging, but ultimately rewarding experience that took me from manually managing resources to orchestrating a fully automated GitOps pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn&amp;rsquo;t just a project showcase. It&amp;rsquo;s a story about the power of starting with the fundamentals, embracing the &amp;ldquo;manual&amp;rdquo; way to build deep understanding, and then leveraging that knowledge to build a professional, automated workflow. If you&amp;rsquo;re on a similar path, I hope my story resonates and offers some useful insights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Todo App Journey An Automated Cloud-Native Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-todo-app-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-todo-app-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction-the-project-that-taught-me-everything&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction: The Project That Taught Me Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of DevOps, you can read documentation for months, but nothing solidifies your skills like building something real. For me, that &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; was a seemingly simple Todo application. This project, inspired by the practical challenges presented in &lt;code&gt;devopswithkubernetes.com&lt;/code&gt;, became my personal deep dive into Kubernetes, taking me from the humble beginnings of &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt; on my local machine to orchestrating a state-of-the-art, multi-environment GitOps workflow on Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Story of This Very Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/devops-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/devops-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a passionate individual eager to delve into the world of DevOps, I found myself facing a common question: &amp;ldquo;What is a good beginner project to gain practical experience?&amp;rdquo; After exploring various resources and communities, I stumbled upon an insightful blog post titled &amp;ldquo;The Best DevOps Project for a Beginner&amp;rdquo; by Logan Marchione. Inspired by his guidance, I embarked on an exciting journey to build my own static website, and I would like to share my personal experience and lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
